The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Miscellaneous deeds relating to Lancashire, [c 1265]-1859; GB/418/B31/1-B33/200; GB/418/Bailey/13; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Richard Hoghton to William de Levesay and Katherine his wife of messuages, lands and tenements in Walton in le Dale and Levesay, 1442; GB/418/B33/169; GB/418/Bailey/13/172; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John Banastre, William Banastre, John Longley, Richard Sergeant, Thomas Eston
  - Attornment from Richard Hoghton and Ralph del Cliffe, chaplain to John Hulton to give seisin to William Levesay of lands and tenements in Walton le Dale and Levesay, 1452; GB/418/B33/170; GB/418/Bailey/13/173; Chetham's Library
  - Extract from court roll, 1523; GB/418/B33/171; GB/418/Bailey/13/174; Chetham's Library
    John Wodecok held a tenement in Walton formerly held in Socage at a rent of 9s 6d by Levesay
  - Bond in £200 from Anne Langton of Lightshaye, widow of Edward Langton, Thomas Langton, and Henry Osbaldstone gent to Thomas Langton to abide by an arbitration, 26 Jan 1566; GB/418/B33/172; GB/418/Bailey/13/175; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Robert Abbot of Cockersand to Sir Thomas Langton of Walton in le Dale of Manor of Westhaughton and Burgage in Preston, 14 Sep 1538; GB/418/B33/173; GB/418/Bailey/13/176; Chetham's Library
    Terms: 99 years, 100 marks
    Annual rent £5 14s 11d
  - Conveyance of manor of Ashdene in Walist Wysil (?Welsh Whittle), 1373; GB/418/B33/174; GB/418/Bailey/13/177; Chetham's Library
    from Robert de Boulton, John de Bryddishirsill, chaplain and Richard de Wolffandene to Robert de Charton, Roger his brother and Thomas de Wadyngton
  - Attornments from Evan Haydock to Henry Browne to give possession of messuages, tenements etc, 3 Dec 1502; GB/418/B33/175; GB/418/Bailey/13/178; Chetham's Library
    Whittle in the Woods and Heapey
    messuages etc formerly belonging to Thurston, son of Richard Bonke, Thomas Standyssh son of Christopher Standish
  - Sherriff's Warrant (Sir Edward Stanley) to Bailiffs of Leylondshire and Constables of Wheleton and Heapey, 17 May 1518; GB/418/B33/176; GB/418/Bailey/13/179; Chetham's Library
    to replevy the cattle of Evan Haydok destrained and seized by Robert Haydok and Richard Marton
  - Receipt from Vane Haydock to John Brereworth Jr for 16s 2d paid for lands and tenements in Withnill, 12 Feb 1504; GB/418/B33/177; GB/418/Bailey/13/180; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Robert Wolmesley, John Brereworth Sr, John Brynhill, John Whitehill, Robert Haydok of Wheleton
  - Conveyance from John son of Robert de Legh to James de Bagylegh, rector of Stockport of land and tenements in Wythenshagh (Wythenshawe) for life, 1396; GB/418/B33/178; GB/418/Bailey/13/181; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Henry Neyctegale Sen. to Henry de Standisse, chaplain of land and tenements in Worneton, Coppul and Blainscough, nd [c 1308]; GB/418/B33/179; GB/418/Bailey/13/182; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Adam Banastre, William de Bradissawe, Henry de Lee, William Lord of Worneton, Richard the Chaplain
    Original and ancient transcript
  - Conveyance from Adam son of Adam de Blaynescogheved (Blainscough) to Adam son of Robert le Taillour of Lathom of lands in Worthington, 24 Aug 1310; GB/418/B33/180; GB/418/Bailey/13/183; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William Worthinton, Hugh de Standische, William de Standische, Henry del Burgh, John de Cophull, John de Chisenhale. Original, ancient and Victorian transcripts
  - Conveyance from William de Worthyngton and John, to Henry son of John Nightegale of land in Worthington, 1315; GB/418/B33/181; GB/418/Bailey/13/184; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William de Thorp, John Nyghtegale, John de Chessenale and others
    Fragmentary original, ancient and Victorian transcripts
  - Quitclaim from Jordon de Buleleghe and Adam his son to John del [?], 1315; GB/418/B33/182; GB/418/Bailey/13/185; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Richard de Linaker to Henry Nightegale of land in Worthington and Blainscough, nd [c 1320]; GB/418/B33/183; GB/418/Bailey/13/186; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William de Stanedische, William de Worthynton, John de Copphul, John de Chesonale, Robert del le Hoo, Robert de Pynesyton, clerk
  - Ancient and Victorian transcripts of conveyance from Henry de Standisse chaplain to Henry Neyctegale the elder of lands in Worneton (Worthington), Cophul (Coppull) and Blainscough, nd [c 1320]; GB/418/B33/184; GB/418/Bailey/13/187; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Adam Banastre, William de Bradessnawe, Henry de Lee, William dominus de Worneton, Richard the chaplain
    Also Victorian transcript and miscellaneous 19th century notes, some in shorthand and probably by Bailey
  - Conveyance from John de Perbourne to John Nytghgale of land in Worthinton and Copull a hamlet of Blagjuneschogh, 1336/7; GB/418/B33/185; GB/418/Bailey/13/188; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Standisch, William de Worthinton, William de Anderton, William del Burgh, Richard de Standisch
  - Conveyance from Henry, son of Adam de Blainscough to Alice daughter of Adam de Middleshagh of land in Coppull and Worthington, 1345; GB/418/B33/186; GB/418/Bailey/13/189; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Standissh, William de Worthinton, Robert de Prestenore, William son of Robert de Worthinton, Roger de Chisevale, Robert the clerk
  - Conveyance from Henry, son of Adam de Blayneschogh to Alice daughter of Elene Wynande of Countyard in Worthington, 1346; GB/418/B33/187; GB/418/Bailey/13/190; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William de Worthinton, John de Derbyshire, John de Nytghale, Robert son of Henry, Robert the clerk
  - Conveyance from William de Worthinton and Thomas de Adlynton to Eve de Perburne of land in Worthington and Adlington, 1346; GB/418/B33/188; GB/418/Bailey/13/191; Chetham's Library
    Written in Anglo-Norman French
  - Quitclaim from Henry son of Adam de Blaynescogh to Alice Daughter of Elene Wynand of land in Worthington and Coppull, 1347; GB/418/B33/189; GB/418/Bailey/13/192; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Standish, William de Worthinton, Robert de Prestecote, John Nythgale, John de Derbischir, Adam le Taylour
  - Conveyance from John, son of Richard Uttynge of Burhull to Thomas de Copphull and Amisie his wife of land in Worthington and Coppull, 1350; GB/418/B33/190; GB/418/Bailey/13/193; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Stanedisch, William de Anderton, Henry de Chernok, Roger de Chesinhale, Thomas de Eccleston, Richard de Longetre, Richard son of Hugh, Henry de Asshon
  - Receipt from Thomas Gerard to Ralph and Richard de Worthyngton (Worthington) of 5 marks in part payment of 10 marks, 1400; GB/418/B33/191; GB/418/Bailey/13/194; Chetham's Library
  - Deed referring to Thomas de Worthinton and William, son of Hugh de Worthington, 1377; GB/418/B33/192; GB/418/Bailey/13/195; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William Barcroft of Barcroft and Richard Crowder of Waddeworth to Richard Hichdon of Worsthorne of messuages lands and tenements in Worsthorn, 1553; GB/418/B33/193; GB/418/Bailey/13/196; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Adam de Katinhale to Thomas, son of Thomas Banastre of land in Wrightington, nd [c 1280]; GB/418/B33/194; GB/418/Bailey/13/197; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry de Lee, Adam Banastre, John de Sharp, Richard de Hassor, Henry de Derbyshire, Thomas de Haslindon
  - Conveyance from Thomas Banestre to Roger Banestre of land in Wrightington, nd [c 1282]; GB/418/B33/195; GB/418/Bailey/13/198; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Edward de Lathom to Emmot, wife of William Sparowe of land and tenements in Wrightington, 1390; GB/418/B33/196; GB/418/Bailey/13/199; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Lord John de Dalton, Geoffrey de Wrytynton, Nicholas de Rigby, John de Asshurst
  - Bond in 40 marks, 1390; GB/418/B33/197; GB/418/Bailey/13/200; Chetham's Library
    from William [?], John de Ballynge, Richard de Scaresbrec, William son of Adam de Penbalt, Roger Gepson, John Lancerman, Robert Banastre de Wrightinton to Emmote, formerly wife of William Sparowe, John del Carr of Lathum and Elene his wife
  - Conveyance from William Abraham, vicar of Croston to Ralph de Worthington and Johanna his wife of messuages, lands and tenements in Worthington, 1475; GB/418/B33/198; GB/418/Bailey/13/201; Chetham's Library
  - Transcript and translation of original deed concerning a bond, 1347; GB/418/B33/199; GB/418/Bailey/13/202; Chetham's Library
    Contains references to John de Trafford of Newcroft, Henry Trafford of Newcroft, Roger de Westleigh of Irwellian, Henry de Wykleswick, Thomas son of Richard, William Sergeant of Urmston, Robert de Glasebrok
  - Transcript and translation of lease from Oliver de Chaderton, William Strangways and Henry Morlands, vicar of Rochdale to John de Crompton of Crompton Hall, 1442; GB/418/B33/200; GB/418/Bailey/13/203; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John Chetham, John Longley, Elia Bulkley
  - Conveyance from John Starkey of Aughton to James Aspenwalgh and Edmund Lord of land in Aughton co Lancs, 14 Jan 1552; GB/418/B35/265; GB/418/Bailey/13/204; Chetham's Library
  - Demise from George Hogd to Francis Brundered of land in Chorlton, 1 Dec 1774; GB/418/B35/266; GB/418/Bailey/13/205; Chetham's Library
  - Reversion of right from John Hyde to Richard Wright concerning land in Flixton, 14 Jul 1631; GB/418/B35/267; GB/418/Bailey/13/206; Chetham's Library
  - Deed of Covenant from John Wright to Edward Simkin to sue for recovery of an estate in Flixton, 13 Mar 1649; GB/418/B35/268; GB/418/Bailey/13/207; Chetham's Library
  - Surrender and reversion of right from Ellen Wright to John Wright concerning land in Flixton, 6 Mar 1649; GB/418/B35/269; GB/418/Bailey/13/208; Chetham's Library
  - Transfer of recovery of land in Flixton, Mar 1650; GB/418/B35/270; GB/418/Bailey/13/209; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Sir Thomas Barton to Edmund Cockshut of messuage and lands in Flixton, 13 Dec 1626; GB/418/B35/271; GB/418/Bailey/13/210; Chetham's Library
  - Feoffment from John Hyde to Richard Wright of messuage and lands in Flixton, 2 Apr 1631; GB/418/B35/272; GB/418/Bailey/13/211; Chetham's Library
  - Joan Taylor's Deed of appropriation of £200 pursuant to her - power reserved in the Deed of Uses, 12 Nov 1706; GB/418/B35/273; GB/418/Bailey/13/212; Chetham's Library
  - Deed from John and Joan Taylor to George Kenyon to lead the uses of a fine of Wright's estate in Flixton, 10 Aug 1706; GB/418/B35/274; GB/418/Bailey/13/213; Chetham's Library
  - Release of Wright's estate in Flixton from Ann Wright and other trustees of John Wright's will to Joan Taylor, 2 Apr 1706; GB/418/B35/275; GB/418/Bailey/13/214; Chetham's Library
  - Deed from George Kenyon to John Taylor (concerning land in Flixton), 14 Aug 1707; GB/418/B35/276; GB/418/Bailey/13/215; Chetham's Library
    Catalogue note: purpose of deed 'uncertain'
  - Deed of uses of a fine levied of an estate in Flixton belonging to Peter Bent and Ellen his wife, 4 Aug 1722; GB/418/B35/277; GB/418/Bailey/13/216; Chetham's Library
  - Release from Thomas Pearson to Peter Bent of land in Flixton, 1 May 1729; GB/418/B35/278; GB/418/Bailey/13/217; Chetham's Library
  - Chirograph of a fine relating to land in Flixton, 9 Aug 1722; GB/418/B35/279; GB/418/Bailey/13/218; Chetham's Library
  - Recovery of land in Flixton from Lawrence Wilson and Joseph Wilson against Henry Wilson and John Bolton, 24 Mar 1739; GB/418/B35/280; GB/418/Bailey/13/219; Chetham's Library
  - Bargain and sale from Ann Wright and others to Joan Taylor of land in Flixton, 1 Apr 1706; GB/418/B35/281; GB/418/Bailey/13/220; Chetham's Library
  - Lease for a year from Benjamin Jameson and Sarah his wife to William Shawe and John Grimshawe of land in Flixton, 12 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/282; GB/418/Bailey/13/221; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Thomas Jefferys alias Jefferson to Richard Millatt and his trustee of land in Flixton, 23 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/283; GB/418/Bailey/13/222; Chetham's Library
  - Release from Benjamin Jameson and Sarah his wife to William Shawe and John Grimshawe to make tenants to the precipe for suffering a recovery of messuage and lands in Flixton, 13 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/284; GB/418/Bailey/13/223; Chetham's Library
    Lancaster assizes 14 March 1770
  - Recovery from Thomas Eastwood to William Shawe, John Grimshawe, Benjamin Jameson and Sarah his wife of land in Flixton, 14 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/285; GB/418/Bailey/13/224; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Thomas Jefferys alias Jefferson to Richard Millatt of messuage and land in Flixton, 24 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/286; GB/418/Bailey/13/225; Chetham's Library
  - Additional security from Richard Millatt and trustee to Isaac Worthington of messuage and lands in Flixton, 26 Mar 1770; GB/418/B35/287; GB/418/Bailey/13/226; Chetham's Library
  - Mortgage from Benjamin Jameson to John Gerrard of several messuages and tenements in Flixton, 25 Oct 1774; GB/418/B35/288; GB/418/Bailey/13/227; Chetham's Library
  - Agreement between John Brundrett, Alice Rogers and Richard Wright concerning land in Flixton, 5 Aug 1809; GB/418/B35/289; GB/418/Bailey/13/228; Chetham's Library
  - Grant and release in fee from Samuel Wood to Robert Brundrett of land in Flixton, Sep 1859; GB/418/B35/290; GB/418/Bailey/13/229; Chetham's Library
  - Grant and confirmation from Roger Langton to William Huson of land in Preston, 10 Mar 1615; GB/418/B35/291; GB/418/Bailey/13/230; Chetham's Library
  - Receipts of Adam Cooper and Richard Atkinson of Preston, 1712; GB/418/B35/292; GB/418/Bailey/13/231; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Richard Massy of Rixton to Thomas Marsh of Land in Rixton, 29 May 1721; GB/418/B35/293; GB/418/Bailey/13/232; Chetham's Library
  - Appearance at Rochdale Manor court by James Feilden before John Byrom concerning possession of land in Rochdale, Lancs, 27 Mar 1594; GB/418/B35/296; GB/418/Bailey/13/233; Chetham's Library
  - Bond from James Feilden to Robert Wolfenden, 7 Mar 1651; GB/418/B35/297; GB/418/Bailey/13/234; Chetham's Library
    Hundersfield, Lancs
  - Abstract of lease of Rochdale Rectory granted by Archbishop of Canterbury to Thomas Parry of Lambeth, 27 Apr 1765; GB/418/B35/298; GB/418/Bailey/13/235; Chetham's Library
  - Admission of William Newall to certain copyhold premises in Hundersfield (Rochdale), 28 Dec 1836; GB/418/B35/299; GB/418/Bailey/13/236; Chetham's Library
  - Admission of Hugh Race, James Hudson and Henry Newall to Lychate in Hundersfield (Rochdale), 19 Apr 1839; GB/418/B35/300; GB/418/Bailey/13/237; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Francis Shevington of Boothes to James Unsworth of Westleigh of land in Shevington, Lancs, 2 Feb 1648; GB/418/B35/301; GB/418/Bailey/13/238; Chetham's Library
  - Early 18th century copy of deed concerning land at Abbeystead, Lancs, (10 Apr 1610); GB/418/B35/302; GB/418/Bailey/13/239; Chetham's Library
- Deeds relating to Cheshire, 1310-1808; GB/418/B33/201-B39/335; GB/418/Bailey/14; Chetham's Library
  - Count Baron of Sir Randall Crewe, Knight (Audley Fee), 1617; GB/418/B33/201; GB/418/Bailey/14/1; Chetham's Library
  - Marriage settlement, 1419; GB/418/B33/202; GB/418/Bailey/14/2; Chetham's Library
    Ralph de Chyldray of Congleton to John de Kuyperley who gave to Alice, daughter and heiress of John de Chyldrey, son of Ralph, lands and tenements in Buglenton
  - Transcript of quitclaim from Margery, daughter of William Mabitt of Minshull to Ranulph, son of Ralph del Rugges, of lands etc in Haselyton, 3 Feb 1327; GB/418/B33/203a; GB/418/Bailey/14/3; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Wrennbury, Nicholas de la Bruer, Adam le Parker, Robert de Stapelegh, Richard de Brosey, William the clerk
  - Transcript of common bond in £10, [14th century]; GB/418/B33/203b; GB/418/Bailey/14/4; Chetham's Library
    William Arderon, Henry Herlelegh, Ralph Herlelegh and Robert Redford to Richard Smyth, to abide the award of Peter Shakkerley and Thomas Langley
  - Transcript of quitclaim from Richard de Boulton to Henry his son of land in Little Bolton, 8 Sep 1326; GB/418/B33/203c; GB/418/Bailey/14/5; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry de Trafford, Richard de Hulton, John de Hulton, Adam de Hulton, Robert de Eclis, Nicholas the clerk
  - Bargain and sale from James Assheton of Spaldying to Edmunde Assheton and William Bretland of Thornclyff of Oldfield in Holynworthe (Hollinworth), 8 Mar 1545; GB/418/B33/204; GB/418/Bailey/14/6; Chetham's Library
    Original and transcript
  - Conveyance from Jordan le Davenpord to Thomas de Heilton, chaplain, of half a burgage in Macclesfield, 1366; GB/418/B33/205; GB/418/Bailey/14/7; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William, son of Reginald Coke to Nicholas Rainow and Margery his wife of one cell in Macclesfield, 1406; GB/418/B33/206; GB/418/Bailey/14/8; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Robert Legh, Roger Alcok, William Slogh, Adam de Bedryngton, Stephan Blagge
  - Conveyance from Margery, lately wife of Nicholas Raynow of Macclesfield, widow, of two cells in Macclesfield, 1432; GB/418/B33/207; GB/418/Bailey/14/9; Chetham's Library
    to Roger le Venables, parson of Routhestorn and John Blomer, parson of Chedle, Thomas del Lock chaplain and Hugh Bryan
    Witnesses: Stephen del Roeit, John le Dutton, John de Legh of Regge, Roger Falibrome, John Tryket
  - Conveyance from Richard de Bydulf, brother and heir of John Bydulf of Kele of a burgage, garden and tenements in Macclesfield, 1432; GB/418/B33/208; GB/418/Bailey/14/10; Chetham's Library
    to Roger de Venables, parson of Routhestorn, John Blomer, parson of Chedle, Thomas del Leth, chaplain and Hugh Byran
  - Conveyance from Thomas Kynsy and Agnes his wife, daugher of Lyulph de Sparton and Matilda, sister of Agnes to William de Baggylegh of 2 messuages and 16 plots of land at Norworthen and Kenworthy, 1310; GB/418/B33/209; GB/418/Bailey/14/11; Chetham's Library
  - Attornment from Geoffrey le Brggelegh to Robert Masei of Sale to give seisin to Geoffrey's father William of land at Norwaurthun and Kenewourtheye (Norworthen and Kenewourtheye), 1322; GB/418/B33/210; GB/418/Bailey/14/12; Chetham's Library
  - Marriage settlement, nd [c 1326]; GB/418/B33/211; GB/418/Bailey/14/13; Chetham's Library
    Cecilia le Masey, widow to Henry de Carleel and Aricie, dau. of Cecilia. 1 assant called sibilirudding, 1 messuage toft and croft, 1 selim in middeleye, 3 selims in le Bothom
    Witnesses: Geoffrey de Chedle, Richard de Stokport, William de Baggel, Roger de Keneworthey, John de Baynchull, Hugh de Brounhall, Roger the clerk
  - Conveyance from William de Baggelegh to John, son of Roger de Kenewortheye (Kenworthy) of 1 selim of land in exchange for another selin, 1339; GB/418/B33/212; GB/418/Bailey/14/14; Chetham's Library
  - Quitclaim from Robert de Tatton of Kenworthei to his sons Robert and William and wife Margaret of all claims, actions etc, 1389; GB/418/B33/213; GB/418/Bailey/14/15; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William de Legh, John his brother, Richard del Broime
  - Conveyance from William de Tatton to William de Lunte and Margaret his wife of land called Lamputter in exchange of land called Russhey Ley, 1414; GB/418/B33/214; GB/418/Bailey/14/16; Chetham's Library
    Norworthyn
  - Conveyance from Robert de Hull of Kenworthy to John de Wydale, Robert de Wydale and Richard, son of John de Wydale of messuages, lands and rent, 1419; GB/418/B33/215; GB/418/Bailey/14/17; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Thomas de Legh of Bagylegh, William de Tatton, Ralph le Vawdray
  - Will of Robert del Pochurn of Stockport, 1416; GB/418/B33/216; GB/418/Bailey/14/18; Chetham's Library
  - Rental of the Manor of Tattenhall with Siddenhall, Newton Golborn, Bellwe and Burwardsley, 1612; GB/418/B33/217; GB/418/Bailey/14/19; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Richard Maystersome to Richard del le of Wico Malbo chaplain, of land in Vicus Hospitalis in Wich Malbank (Nantwich), 1427; GB/418/B33/218; GB/418/Bailey/14/20; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Kyngsley, John son of John de Wetenhall, Richard Alna
  - Court Roll of Countess of Warwick's fee (part of Manor of Nantwich) at Court held at Nantwich, 7 May 1589; GB/418/B33/219; GB/418/Bailey/14/21; Chetham's Library
  - Decree of burial place etc. in chancel of Ashton-on-Mersey church, co Ches, 27 Oct 1637; GB/418/B36/303; GB/418/Bailey/14/22; Chetham's Library
  - Mortgage for £24 from Joseph Goodier to Samuel Holbrooke for land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 1 May 1751; GB/418/B36/304; GB/418/Bailey/14/23; Chetham's Library
    Paid off 9 April 1753
  - Feoffment from Richard Wainman to Joseph Goodier of cottage and lands in Ashton upon Mersey, Ches, 10 Apr 1751; GB/418/B36/305; GB/418/Bailey/14/24; Chetham's Library
  - Mortgage for £23 from Joseph Goodier to Rev. Whitaker et al for land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 10 Apr 1753; GB/418/B36/306; GB/418/Bailey/14/25; Chetham's Library
  - Will of Joseph Goodier of Ashton-on-Mersey, butcher, 5 Apr 1760; GB/418/B36/307; GB/418/Bailey/14/26; Chetham's Library
    Paper
    Probate issued 25 March 1761
  - Release from John Goodier et al to Thomas Davies and James Kay for their shares of a legacy from the late Joseph Goodier of Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 8 May 1775; GB/418/B36/308; GB/418/Bailey/14/27; Chetham's Library
  - Mortgage from William Bowker to John Creasty of Cottage and land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 11 May 1775; GB/418/B36/309; GB/418/Bailey/14/28; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from executors of Joseph Goodier to William Bowker of a cottage and lands in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 9 May 1775.; GB/418/B36/310; GB/418/Bailey/14/29; Chetham's Library
  - Bargain and sale from William Bowker to John Derbyshire of land in Ashton-upon-Mersey, Ches, 24 Mar 1783; GB/418/B36/311; GB/418/Bailey/14/30; Chetham's Library
  - Release from William Bowker to John Derbyshire of land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 23 Mar 1783; GB/418/B36/312; GB/418/Bailey/14/31; Chetham's Library
    Also assignment of a term to attend the fee
  - Lease for one year from William Royle and his wife to Edward Pearson of land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 2 Nov 1801; GB/418/B36/313; GB/418/Bailey/14/32; Chetham's Library
  - Mortgage fee from William Royle and his wife to Edward Pearson for land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 3 Nov 1801; GB/418/B36/314; GB/418/Bailey/14/33; Chetham's Library
    Covenant to levy fine and declaration of its uses. Declaration of outstanding terms affecting this estate
  - Lease for one year from Edward Pearson to John Sherlock of land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 1 Nov 1808; GB/418/B36/315; GB/418/Bailey/14/34; Chetham's Library
  - Indenture of fine between Edward Pearson, plaintiff, William Royle and his wife deforciants of premises in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 21 Apr 1802; GB/418/B36/316; GB/418/Bailey/14/35; Chetham's Library
    Chester Spring Assizes
  - Conveyance from William Royle, Mary his wife and George Ashton to Edward Pearson of land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 29 Mar 1803; GB/418/B36/317; GB/418/Bailey/14/36; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Edward Pearson to John Sherlock of land in Ashton-on-Mersey, Ches, 2 Nov 1808; GB/418/B36/318; GB/418/Bailey/14/37; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Sir George Warburton of Arley to William Dutton of Great Budworth of land in Great Budworth, Ches, 17 Jan 1728; GB/418/B36/319; GB/418/Bailey/14/38; Chetham's Library
  - Lease from Sir George Warburton of Arley to William Dutton of Great Budworth of land in Great Budworth, 28 Aug 1733; GB/418/B36/320; GB/418/Bailey/14/39; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William Davenport of Bramall (Bramhall) to his son Peter of land in Davenport in the occupation of Lawrence Bancrofte, 25 Feb 1582; GB/418/B36/321; GB/418/Bailey/14/40; Chetham's Library